<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>posts on Mildly Journaling</title>
    <link>https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in posts on Mildly Journaling</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 13:38:19 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Entrepreneurship is being wildly optimistic</title>
      <link>https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/entrepreneur-wildly-optimistic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 13:38:19 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/entrepreneur-wildly-optimistic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Quick thought: Entrepreneurship, at its core, requires wild optimism.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The thought struck me while watching an interview with a tech executive explaining why their latest product launch failed and received overwhelmingly negative reviews. The details of the failure weren’t what stood out—instead, it was the optimistic tone the executive used while reflecting on the situation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this context, optimism simply means having the willingness to try and the confidence that it will succeed. The opposite would be seeing all the challenges and deciding it will fail before even attempting it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That interview reminded me of the conversations, interviews, and podcasts I’ve listened to about how people start and grow their businesses. A common thread is how deeply these founders believe in their vision and pour everything into it—especially when things get tough (like running out of money, facing lawsuits, or other crises). Many describe how they just kept going until something finally clicked. Of course, for every success story, there are many that don’t make it. Still, this kind of radical optimism seems essential—it helps people see past immediate obstacles and stay focused on the possibility of future success.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Another recurring theme is how naive and overly optimistic people often are when they first start a business. Many say they had no idea how hard it would be—and admit that, had they known, they might not have done it at all. That initial optimism seems to serve as a kind of fuel, propelling them past the early barriers and toward the “rainbow” they believe is just ahead.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Call it faith, vision, ambition—or maybe just delusion—but at the heart of entrepreneurship is a bold optimism about the future. It’s what drives people to do things others wouldn’t dare or even understand—for better or worse.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quick notes - How Does OAuth Work</title>
      <link>https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/how-does-oauth-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2025 14:54:34 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/how-does-oauth-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I am building a web app that pulls user data from an Internet consumer social app. In order for the app user to grant access to my web app to read their data, the app uses an OAuth flow to authorize the user and grant access to the client (my web app). Here are some quick notes about OAuth that I learned through the process.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;OAuth stands for Open Authorization because it is an open source authorization framework&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There are two versions of OAuth (1.0/2.0) and people usually mean OAuth 2.0 when they mention OAuth&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;OAuth is used for users of service A to grant access to their service A data to service B&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;OAuth makes it possible to authorize data access without involving user credentials (i.e. passwords)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A typical OAuth flow involves 4 entities:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;resource owner: users of the app&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;client: the server that requests access&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;authorization server: the server that coordinates the authorization flow&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;resource server: where the user data actually resides&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A typical OAuth flow:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The client requests authorization from the authorization server, supplying its identification obtained from the latter before&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The authorization server authenticates the client and verifies that the requested scopes are permitted&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The user interacts with the authorization server to grant access&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The authorization server redirects back to the client with either an access token&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The client requests access to the said resource from the resource server using the token&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investment Update - May 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/investment-update-05-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 13:21:01 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/investment-update-05-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the 5th post of the monthly family investment update. The post tracks the performance in the month of May, 2025. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/investment-update-01-2025/&#34;&gt;The first post&lt;/a&gt; contains some explanation of why and how we are doing this.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Overall, our family investment asset continues the growth trend started last month. It was &lt;strong&gt;100.47&lt;/strong&gt; at the end of last month and &lt;strong&gt;108.30&lt;/strong&gt; at the end of this month, with a positive growth of &lt;strong&gt;6.09%&lt;/strong&gt;. The total value finally climbs over the previous peak (104.85 at the end of January). May has also been the month with the highest growth so far.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A breakdown of growth by investment type is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;table&gt;&#xA;  &lt;thead&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;          &lt;th&gt;Growth rate (%)&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/thead&gt;&#xA;  &lt;tbody&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Total asset&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;6.09&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;After tax&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;6.32&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;401(k)&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;5.46&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/tbody&gt;&#xA;&lt;/table&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The After tax portion outperforms the 401(k) portion again this month. The overall growth trails both that of S&amp;amp;P index (6.29%) and NASDAQ Comp. (9.65%) (&lt;a href=&#34;https://ccmg.com/benchmark-review-monthly-recap-may-2025/&#34;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the annual goal this year for our investment asset is to lower its portion of stock holdings. The shift reverts a little bit in May:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;table&gt;&#xA;  &lt;thead&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;          &lt;th&gt;Ratio (%)&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/thead&gt;&#xA;  &lt;tbody&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Individual stocks&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;39.07%&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Funds&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;26.39%&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Cash&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;37.12%&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/tbody&gt;&#xA;&lt;/table&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The cash portion declines from 42.26% to 37.12%. This is mostly due to a increase of investment in both individual stocks and funds. Overall I&amp;rsquo;m still comfortable with the ratio.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I tried 3D Printer for the first time</title>
      <link>https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/i-tried-3d-printer-for-the-first-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 19:56:56 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/i-tried-3d-printer-for-the-first-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently have been using a 3D printer to print stuff, and here are what I printed:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/3d_print_1.png&#34; alt=&#34;A showcase of the 3 items I 3D-printed&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was a lot of fun! The thing in front is a cable organizer, and the two in behind are the same - a spiral fidget toy. The fidget toy has 2 parts and can be split like this:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/3d_print_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;The two separate parts of the fidget toys&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This all started when I notice the local library has a 3D printer that anybody can book for a 2-hour session to print whatever they would like to print. The only requirement is the print time has to be within 2 hours and the item is compatible with the printer. I have used 3 sessions so far. The larger fidget takes nearly 2 hours to finish, and the other two takes about 1 hour each.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The printer at the library is called &lt;a href=&#34;https://ultimaker.com/3d-printers/s-series/ultimaker-s5/&#34;&gt;Ultimaker S5&lt;/a&gt;. The library offers PLA materials in various colors for us to pick and use for printing. I don&amp;rsquo;t have a good idea about what grade this printer is, but it is quite easy to use. The library staff helped me during the first session, but for the following sessions I just go and print it on my own.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of steps I need to do:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;select a design from a 3D printing website called &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thingiverse.com&#34;&gt;thingyverse&lt;/a&gt; and download its file(s)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;load them into Ultimaker software called Cura, and configure the files&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;load the files into the drive and plug it to the printer&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;load materials onto the printer&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;select the file to print&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The library provides a computer for me to choose , and also an USB drive to transfer the file to the printer. Of course for advanced users they can always design their own files at home and bring them here just for printing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As for the configurations, I have only used a few basic ones:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;enlarge or shrink the item size: mostly latter to ensure the print time is within limit&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;enable adhesive: the printer will add a layer on the bottom as a foundation so the item does not wobble during the printing&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;choose one or two nozzles: if the item has 2 separate parts then two nozzles can print them in parallel and reduce the print time in half; having two nozzles also allows printing in 2 different colors&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;choose how thick the print is: the thinner the nozzle output is, the smoother the finish will be, with a longer print time&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I use the medium thickness for all three prints to ensure the print time is within the limit - can&amp;rsquo;t remember the exact numbers. It shows if you take a closer look at the finish:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/3d_print_3.png&#34; alt=&#34;Closer look of the print finish&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/3d_print_4.png&#34; alt=&#34;Another closer look of the print finish&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Overall my experience of 3D printer is very good - being able to make a toy or small item out of nothing (almost) is a bit magical. However, the print efficiency is indeed slow, and the finish is def inferior compared with that of actual industrial/commercial items.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My next goal is to explore the printer at the library more and see if I can print things with more complex structure or a better finish.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I use a LLM to automatically categorize bank transactions</title>
      <link>https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/what-is-ai-dev-and-my-first-ai-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 08:07:28 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/what-is-ai-dev-and-my-first-ai-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I write a program to automatically categorize bank transactions into one of the predefined categories (like Groceries, Shopping, Travel, etc), like this oen below:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;  {&#xA;    &amp;#34;id&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;083df275-8b29-49a7-8cd5-888bfa52xxxx&amp;#34;,&#xA;    &amp;#34;date&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;10/07/2024&amp;#34;,&#xA;    &amp;#34;amount&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;-11.51&amp;#34;,&#xA;    &amp;#34;description&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;PANDA EXPRESS # xxxx&amp;#34;,,&#xA;    &amp;#34;category&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Food &amp;amp; Drink&amp;#34;,&#xA;    &amp;#34;model_guess&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Food&amp;#34;&#xA;  },&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;category&lt;/code&gt; is part of the transaction - some transactions have it some don&amp;rsquo;t it. &lt;code&gt;model_guess&lt;/code&gt; is the output of the program. You can find the program code &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/yyl/ai-tools/blob/main/auto_cat.py&#34;&gt;here on Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The main motivation is privacy. There are a lot of personal finance services out there with great features, but they either require me to upload bank data to their website, or share bank credentials so they can pull data directly. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to do either of them. Instead, I&amp;rsquo;d like something to do what I want locally - nothing fancy, just some simple summary of my spend and breakdown by year, month and category is more than sufficient. That narrows the problem to categorize transactions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are many existing work. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/robintw/BankClassify&#34;&gt;This&lt;/a&gt; one overall is the best but it requires user to manually review every label and requires extra processing for different bank format; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/eli-goodfriend/banking-class&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; one comes with too many bags e.g. it still depends on Python 2; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/j-convey/MoneyMap-AI#&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; one requires powerful GPUs to train the model at the first place.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Majority of the transactions actually already have a category value assigned by the bank and I do trust their correctness. For them, I just need to unify categories from different banks then that&amp;rsquo;s done. That leaves me transactions without categories - about 25%.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I tried a few ways that didn&amp;rsquo;t work. At first I generate text embedding per transaction and try to cluster them all. The clusters didn&amp;rsquo;t look great, and is very prone to over-cluster. Then I use local LLM to label each transaction - it&amp;rsquo;s a hit or miss at first. At some point I try to use LLM output to train a traditional ML model - but it just sounds too complex for such a single task.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Eventually I settle on the current method - use local LLM but cramming as many as previous categorized examples in the context window, and then build a way to correct LLM output. The script persists everything so the corrected category would also be used as previous example in the next batch of categorizing. I use Gemma 3 which provides 128k context window so very sufficient for my use case. It is also just generally much better at this task than other LLMs (Mistral, Llama, etc).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the first time I incorporate LLM to my program. It takes some time to get used to, especially around making it reliable enough to be used. For example the initial results out of LLM are not good enough until I leverage the context window and put in a lot of previous examples. Writing a program that uses a LLM is very different from the traditional programming, and can be a lot more efficient and powerful than the latter too - I get what is the buzz of AI developers now!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investment Update - April 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/investment-update-04-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 09:21:01 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/investment-update-04-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the 4th post of the monthly family investment update. The post tracks the performance in the month of April, 2025. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/investment-update-01-2025/&#34;&gt;The first post&lt;/a&gt; contains some explanation of why and how we are doing this.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Overall, our family investment asset return to growth after 2 months of decline. It was 96.35 at the end of March and 100.47 at the end of April, with a positive growth of 2.44%. A breakdown is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;table&gt;&#xA;  &lt;thead&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;          &lt;th&gt;Growth rate (%)&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/thead&gt;&#xA;  &lt;tbody&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Total asset&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;2.44&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;After tax&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;3.45&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;401(k)&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;-0.09&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/tbody&gt;&#xA;&lt;/table&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The After tax portion outperforms the 401(k) portion after trailing the latter 2 months in a row. The growth is also better than &lt;a href=&#34;https://ccmg.com/benchmark-review-monthly-recap-april-2025/&#34;&gt;that of the S&amp;amp;P Index and that of NASDAQ Comp.&lt;/a&gt;, which are at -0.68% and 0.88%, respectively. While I don&amp;rsquo;t break down further the asset type, the better-than-index growth is mainly due to a much higher growth of the crypto portion.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the annual goal this year for our investment asset is to lower its portion of stock holdings. There has been a large shift to cash in April:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;table&gt;&#xA;  &lt;thead&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;          &lt;th&gt;Ratio (%)&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/thead&gt;&#xA;  &lt;tbody&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Individual stocks&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;31.20%&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Funds&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;24.40%&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Cash&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;42.26%&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/tbody&gt;&#xA;&lt;/table&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It grows from 18.08% last month to 42.26%, closing to half. This is largely shifted from individual stocks. The purpose of the shift is managing the risk.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning some very basics of music theory</title>
      <link>https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/learning-music-theory-basics-pt1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 11:23:17 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/learning-music-theory-basics-pt1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I have started learning some very basic music theory while also learning to play a digital keyboard. I add some more details of motivation at the bottom. Below is what I have learned so far.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;note&lt;/strong&gt; defines the unit of a sound in music, and can be a letter ranging from A to G&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;measure&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;bar&lt;/strong&gt; is like a bounded space for a bunch of notes&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;time signature&lt;/strong&gt; determines the number of notes of specific types can be in a measure or a bar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;whole/half/quarter&lt;/strong&gt; note takes up one measure in a typical 4/4 time signature (4 beats)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An &lt;strong&gt;octave&lt;/strong&gt; defines the interval between two notes where one having twice the frequency of vibration of the other&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;scale&lt;/strong&gt; is just the sequence of notes that are between one note and its octave&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;major scale&lt;/strong&gt; is a type of scale defined by the intervals between notes&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2 notes can be either whole or half step away from each other&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;major scale has an interval pattern of &lt;code&gt;Whole - Whole - Half - Whole - Whole - Whole - Half&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;major scales tend to sound bright, happy and hopeful&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;C major scale&lt;/strong&gt; starts at a C note, goes to D, E, F, G, A, B and ends at C in the next octave&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;minor scale&lt;/strong&gt; follows the pattern of &lt;code&gt;Whole - Half - Whole - Whole - Half - Whole - Whole&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;chord&lt;/strong&gt; is a combination of three or more musical tones sounded simultaneously to create a harmonic effect&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chord examples: C major chord, A minor chord&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investment Update - March 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/investment-update-03-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 11:21:01 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/investment-update-03-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the 3rd post of the monthly family investment update. The post tracks the performance in the month of March, 2025. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/investment-update-01-2025/&#34;&gt;The first post&lt;/a&gt; contains some explanation of why and how we are doing this.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Overall, our family investment asset shrinks in March, a 2nd time in a row. It was 102.08 in Feb and 96.35 at the end of March, with a negative growth of -7.96%. A breakdown is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;table&gt;&#xA;  &lt;thead&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;          &lt;th&gt;Growth rate (%)&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/thead&gt;&#xA;  &lt;tbody&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Total asset&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;-7.96&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;After tax&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;-9.52&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;401(k)&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;-3.49&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/tbody&gt;&#xA;&lt;/table&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The 401(k) portion still performs better than the after tax portion, relatively. However, the decrease in asset value is even worse than that in February. Zoom out, the S&amp;amp;P Index &lt;a href=&#34;https://ccmg.com/benchmark-review-monthly-recap-march-2025/&#34;&gt;fell 5.63% in March&lt;/a&gt;, and Nasdaq a whopping -8.14%.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the annual goal this year for our investment asset is to lower its portion of stock holdings. As shown below, it&amp;rsquo;s slowly moving towards the goal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;table&gt;&#xA;  &lt;thead&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;          &lt;th&gt;Ratio (%)&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/thead&gt;&#xA;  &lt;tbody&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Individual stocks&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;52.67&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Funds&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;23.78&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Cash&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;18.08&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/tbody&gt;&#xA;&lt;/table&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Compared to that in last month, cash percentage grows from 10.57 to 18.08, and individual stocks are down to 52.67 from 64.84. Note a large portion of funds is also in the stock index funds - the goal is to be less exposed to individual stocks, not the stock market per se. That being said, with all the tariffs news going around, it might not be a good time to keep the index funds either.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jump by word in the command line in iTerm2</title>
      <link>https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/jump-to-anywhere-of-the-command-in-iterm2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 15:08:01 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/jump-to-anywhere-of-the-command-in-iterm2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I use iTerm2 as the terminal in macOS, but the conventional shortcuts &lt;code&gt;ctrl + -&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;-&lt;/code&gt; to quickly jump backward/forward does not work in iTerm2 by default. I am always annoyed by that so I Google a little bit and found the solution. Here&amp;rsquo;s how to set it up (bonus tip at the end):&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/iterm2_keyboard_shortcut.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot of the iTerm2 setting for shortcut to jump around&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Steps:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Open &lt;code&gt;Settings&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Select &lt;code&gt;Profiles&lt;/code&gt; tab&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Select the profile you are using under the &lt;code&gt;Profile Name&lt;/code&gt; (for me it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;Default&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Select &lt;code&gt;Keys&lt;/code&gt; tab, then &lt;code&gt;Key Mappings&lt;/code&gt; tab&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In the &lt;code&gt;Presets...&lt;/code&gt; dropdown, select &lt;code&gt;Natural Text Editing&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Select &lt;code&gt;Keep&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;Remove&lt;/code&gt; when it asks if you want to keep all current mappings before loading the preset (I choose &lt;code&gt;Remove&lt;/code&gt; because I don&amp;rsquo;t have any customized mappings set anyway)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bonus tip: apparently one can also hold &lt;code&gt;option&lt;/code&gt; then click in the command to jump there! I personally still prefer keyboard shortcuts when two hands are on the keyboard though.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I add a newsletter subscription option to my website</title>
      <link>https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/add-follow-it-newsletter-to-my-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 06:20:54 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/add-follow-it-newsletter-to-my-site/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I add a subscribe form so that whoever interested can subscribe to my new post and receive them via email. The form is at the end of every post:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/follow_it_subscribe_form.png&#34; alt=&#34;Subscribe form at the end of the post&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The service I use is called &lt;a href=&#34;https://follow.it&#34;&gt;follow.it&lt;/a&gt;. Its free-tier is quite generous e.g. can only support up to 5 different feeds. For me it&amp;rsquo;s more than generous.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The email looks ok on a desktop:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/follow_it_newsletter_desktop_look.png&#34; alt=&#34;Newsletter look on a desktop&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But less so on a mobile phone:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/follow_it_newsletter_mobile_look.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Newsletter look on a desktop&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It looks a bit crammed - but since it is free, it&amp;rsquo;s a decent starting point!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Save SSH Private Key in Keychain so you don&#39;t need to type it anymore on MacOS</title>
      <link>https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/save-ssh-private-key-in-keychain-and-never-type-it-once-on-macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 06:25:38 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/save-ssh-private-key-in-keychain-and-never-type-it-once-on-macos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/understanding-ssh-and-using-it-to-clone-a-github-repository/&#34;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt; I talk about setting up SSH to connect to Github as a better method than HTTPS to clone Github repository. However, it still requires me to type in my SSH passphrase for every connection:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;yyl@home dir % ssh -T git@github.com&#xA;Enter passphrase for key &amp;#39;/Users/yyl/.ssh/id_ed25519&amp;#39;:    &amp;lt;---- ask for passphrase every time!&#xA;Hi yyl! You&amp;#39;ve successfully authenticated, but GitHub does not provide shell access.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to not need to type it every time. Turns out it is indeed possible MacOS! I followed this &lt;a href=&#34;https://apple.stackexchange.com/a/250572&#34;&gt;great instruction&lt;/a&gt; and it takes me 2 minutes to set it up (Github has the same instruction too although more buried &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.github.com/en/authentication/connecting-to-github-with-ssh/generating-a-new-ssh-key-and-adding-it-to-the-ssh-agent#adding-your-ssh-key-to-the-ssh-agent&#34;&gt;in the SSH setup guide&lt;/a&gt; ). Once I have it set up, I no longer need to type the passphrase when connecting to Github or any host using SSH:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;yyl@home dir % ls -al ~/.ssh    &amp;lt;---- command to see all my ssh keys&#xA;total 32&#xA;drwx------   6 yyl  staff   192 Mar 23 20:27 .&#xA;drwxr-xr-x+ 33 yyl  staff  1056 Mar 24 21:18 ..&#xA;-rw-------   1 yyl  staff   464 Mar 23 19:53 id_ed25519    &amp;lt;---- my private key&#xA;-rw-r--r--   1 yyl  staff    99 Mar 23 19:53 id_ed25519.pub&#xA;-rw-------   1 yyl  staff   828 Mar 23 20:27 known_hosts&#xA;-rw-r--r--   1 yyl  staff    92 Mar 23 15:30 known_hosts.old&#xA;yyl@home dir % ssh-add --apple-use-keychain ~/.ssh/id_ed25519 &amp;lt;---- command to add the private key to keychain&#xA;Enter passphrase for /Users/yyl/.ssh/id_ed25519:    &amp;lt;---- type the passphrase one last time&#xA;Identity added: /Users/yyl/.ssh/id_ed25519 (my_email@gmail.com)&#xA;yyl@home dir % touch ~/.ssh/config    &amp;lt;---- command to create a new config file if not exist&#xA;yyl@home dir % vim ~/.ssh/config    &amp;lt;---- add the Host text from the link to the file&#xA;yyl@home dir % ssh -T git@github.com&#xA;Hi yyl! You&amp;#39;ve successfully authenticated, but GitHub does not provide shell access.    &amp;lt;---- look ma, no passphrase!&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding SSH and using it to clone a Github repository</title>
      <link>https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/understanding-ssh-and-using-it-to-clone-a-github-repository/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 14:47:51 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/understanding-ssh-and-using-it-to-clone-a-github-repository/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this post I try to learn a little bit about SSH, and show you how to clone a Github repository via SSH. I&amp;rsquo;ve scrambled most secrets, keys or identities in the terminal output but it should not affect the reading or the functionality.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have tried to clone some github repositories to my local machine for development lately. The easiest way to do that used to be &lt;code&gt;HTTPS&lt;/code&gt; - &amp;ldquo;Clone using the web URL&amp;rdquo; option: I copy and paste the repo HTTPS URL, run &lt;code&gt;git clone {URL}&lt;/code&gt;, that&amp;rsquo;s it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But now it&amp;rsquo;s been failing:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;yyl@terminal folder % git clone https://github.com/yyl/awesome_repo.git&#xA;Cloning into &amp;#39;awesome_repo&amp;#39;...&#xA;Username for &amp;#39;https://github.com&amp;#39;: yyl&#xA;Password for &amp;#39;https://user@github.com&amp;#39;:&#xA;remote: Support for password authentication was removed on August 13, 2021.&#xA;remote: Please see https://docs.github.com/get-started/getting-started-with-git/about-remote-repositories#cloning-with-https-urls for information on currently recommended modes of authentication.&#xA;fatal: Authentication failed for &amp;#39;https://github.com/user/awesome_repo.git&amp;#39;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.github.com/en/get-started/git-basics/about-remote-repositories#cloning-with-https-urls&#34;&gt;The link in the output&lt;/a&gt; points out that GitHub is no longer accepting account passwords for authentication since August 2021. Instead, users need to create and use &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.github.com/en/authentication/keeping-your-account-and-data-secure/managing-your-personal-access-tokens&#34;&gt;personal access token&lt;/a&gt;. Ouch! I don&amp;rsquo;t wanna use or hold another authentication secret!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Luckily, Github provides a few other ways to clone the repo, including through SSH. In the rest of the post I will demonstrate how I set up SSH on my new Macbook and clone the repo from Github to local. I assume you have a rough idea of what SSH is, and some basic knowledge around using it - don&amp;rsquo;t worry, I will try to explain along the way!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;try-to-connect-via-ssh-the-first-time&#34;&gt;Try to connect via SSH the first time&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;yyl@terminal folder % ssh git@github.com&#xA;The authenticity of host &amp;#39;github.com (xxx.xx.xxx.x)&amp;#39; can&amp;#39;t be established.&#xA;ED25519 key fingerprint is SHA256:xxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxx.&#xA;This key is not known by any other names.&#xA;Are you sure you want to continue connecting (yes/no/[fingerprint])? yes&#xA;Warning: Permanently added &amp;#39;github.com&amp;#39; (ED25519) to the list of known hosts.&#xA;yyl@github.com: Permission denied (publickey).&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;The command (&lt;code&gt;ssh git@github.com&lt;/code&gt;) failed but what it does is try to connect to github.com via the SSH client &lt;code&gt;ssh&lt;/code&gt;. It did a few things:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;it creates the directory &lt;code&gt;~/.ssh&lt;/code&gt; for me: everything related to SSH connections is in here (this is only for using ssh the first time)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;it tries to check it&amp;rsquo;s really &lt;code&gt;github.com&lt;/code&gt; that is connecting with us (server authentication)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;it tries to check the user (me) has the proper credentials the remote server (&lt;code&gt;github.com&lt;/code&gt;) requires (user authentication)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;if both succeeds, establish the connection&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It failed at the 3rd step: the ssh client rejects me as I don&amp;rsquo;t have a valid key pair for authentication yet. The solution? Generate one!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;generate-a-new-pair-of-ssh-keys&#34;&gt;Generate a new pair of SSH keys&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;yyl@terminal folder % ssh-keygen -t ed25519 -C &amp;#34;your_email@example.com&amp;#34;&#xA;&#xA;Generating public/private ed25519 key pair.&#xA;Enter file in which to save the key (~/.ssh/id_ed25519):&#xA;Enter passphrase (empty for no passphrase):&#xA;Enter same passphrase again:&#xA;Your identification has been saved in ~/.ssh/id_ed25519&#xA;Your public key has been saved in ~/.ssh/id_ed25519.pub&#xA;The key fingerprint is:&#xA;SHA256:xxxxxxxxxxxxxx your_email@example.com&#xA;The key&amp;#39;s randomart image is:&#xA;+--[ED25519 256]--+&#xA;| xxxx xx   x     |&#xA;|x xx x x x       |&#xA;|xxx x xxx        |&#xA;|xxxx xxxx x x    |&#xA;|xxx x xx x       |&#xA;|x xx   xxx       |&#xA;|  x    x         |&#xA;|   x   xxx       |&#xA;|       xxxx      |&#xA;+----[SHA256]-----+&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;The command &lt;code&gt;ssh-keygen&lt;/code&gt; generates a new pair of public/private keys on my laptop. It means a few things:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The private key is saved to &lt;code&gt;~/.ssh/id_ed25519&lt;/code&gt; as noted in the output unless one specifies alternative file&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The public key is saved to &lt;code&gt;~/.ssh/id_ed25519.pub&lt;/code&gt; correspondingly&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It asks for a passphrase which will be asked when trying to establish a SSH connection using this key pair&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;randomart&lt;/code&gt; image at the end is a visualization of the key such that people could visually distinguish different keys - I scrabbled mine, usually it would have different symbols inside&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before we try to connect again, I run &lt;code&gt;ls -al ~/.ssh&lt;/code&gt; and this is what I see:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;yyl@terminal folder % ls -al ~/.ssh&#xA;total 24&#xA;drwx------   5 yyl  staff   160 Mar 23 19:53 .&#xA;drwxr-xr-x+ 33 yyl  staff  1056 Mar 23 15:30 ..&#xA;-rw-------   1 yyl  staff   464 Mar 23 19:53 id_ed25519&#xA;-rw-r--r--   1 yyl  staff    99 Mar 23 19:53 id_ed25519.pub&#xA;-rw-r--r--   1 yyl  staff    92 Mar 23 15:30 known_hosts&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;As said now there are a pair of keys inside. Besides that, the file &lt;code&gt;known_hosts&lt;/code&gt; contains all the hosts (remote servers) that I have tried to connect and agree to save to the file. If I look at the file content, it should contain just one host (github.com):&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;yyl@terminal folder % cat ~/.ssh/known_hosts&#xA;github.com ssh-ed25519 xxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxx&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;xxx&lt;/code&gt; part is the public key provided by github.com to us for authentication.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;connect-to-github-with-my-new-keys&#34;&gt;Connect to Github with my new keys&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;OK, with new keys, lets try to connect again:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;yyl@terminal folder % ssh git@github.com&#xA;yyl@github.com: Permission denied (publickey).&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;The server authentication failed again - the remote server (github.com) does not recognize my public key. It turns out we need to &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.github.com/en/authentication/connecting-to-github-with-ssh/adding-a-new-ssh-key-to-your-github-account#adding-a-new-ssh-key-to-your-account&#34;&gt;add the public key to Github website&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After the key is added to the Github account, let&amp;rsquo;s try to connect one more time:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;yyl@terminal folder % ssh -T git@github.com&#xA;Enter passphrase for key &amp;#39;~/.ssh/id_ed25519&amp;#39;:&#xA;Hi yyl! You&amp;#39;ve successfully authenticated, but GitHub does not provide shell access.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Great! The connection is working. Now it&amp;rsquo;s time to clone a repo:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;yyl@terminal folder % git clone git@github.com:yyl/awesome_repo.git&#xA;Cloning into &amp;#39;awesome_repo&amp;#39;...&#xA;Enter passphrase for key &amp;#39;~/.ssh/id_ed25519&amp;#39;:&#xA;remote: Enumerating objects: 26, done.&#xA;remote: Counting objects: 100% (26/26), done.&#xA;remote: Compressing objects: 100% (17/17), done.&#xA;remote: Total 26 (delta 8), reused 25 (delta 7), pack-reused 0 (from 0)&#xA;Receiving objects: 100% (26/26), 12.05 KiB | 4.02 MiB/s, done.&#xA;Resolving deltas: 100% (8/8), done.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investment Update - February 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/investment-update-02-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 17:21:01 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/investment-update-02-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the 2nd post of the monthly update of our family investment asset. The post tracks the performance in the month of February, 2025. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/investment-update-01-2025/&#34;&gt;The first post&lt;/a&gt; contains some explanation of why and how we are doing this.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Overall, our family investment asset shrinks in February. It was 104.85 in January but 102.08 at the end of the February, with a negative growth of -3.47%. A breakdown is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;table&gt;&#xA;  &lt;thead&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;          &lt;th&gt;Growth rate (%)&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/thead&gt;&#xA;  &lt;tbody&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Total asset&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;-3.47&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;After tax&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;-4.35&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;401(k)&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;-0.82&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/tbody&gt;&#xA;&lt;/table&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s easy to see that the 401(k) portion performs better than the after tax portion, relatively. If we zoom out, the S&amp;amp;P Index &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.breckinridge.com/insights/details/february-2025-market-commentary/#:~:text=The%20S%26P%20Index%20fell%201.3,Growth%20Index%20fell%203.6%20percent.&amp;amp;text=Performance%20among%20larger%20capitalization%20and,high%20beta18%20stocks%20lagged..&#34;&gt;fell 1.3% in the February&lt;/a&gt;, while Nasdaq-100 Index &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.invesco.com/apac/en/institutional/insights/etf/nasdaq-100-Index-commentary-february-2025.html&#34;&gt;fell 2.7%&lt;/a&gt;. The after tax portion consists of a large percentage of individual stocks, mostly in the growth sector (tech, telecommunication), so it tracks more like Nasdaq-100 index. The 401(k) portion consists about half in SP500 index fund and half in retirement fund, so tracks more like a smooth-over SP500.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in the first post, the after tax portion is undergoing a reallocation from individual stocks to index funds. Here&amp;rsquo;s the ratio breakdown of the after tax portion as of the end of the February:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;table&gt;&#xA;  &lt;thead&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;          &lt;th&gt;Ratio (%)&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/thead&gt;&#xA;  &lt;tbody&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Individual stocks&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;64.84&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Funds&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;24.59&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Cash&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;10.57&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/tbody&gt;&#xA;&lt;/table&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reading &#34;An Interview With Michael Nathanson About the Streaming Endgame&#34;</title>
      <link>https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/stratechery-an-interview-with-michael-nathanson-about-the-streaming-endgame/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 20:06:44 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/stratechery-an-interview-with-michael-nathanson-about-the-streaming-endgame/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://stratechery.com/2025/an-interview-with-michael-nathanson-about-the-streaming-endgame/&#34;&gt;This interview&lt;/a&gt; goes through a lot of things through the lens of Michael Nathanson, from streaming players, sports industry, to tech industry:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Youtube TV&lt;/strong&gt; from Alphabet has the best potential among all streaming players (Peacock, Paramount Plus, Netflix) because:&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It is the only player that has all channels content including that from other streaming players, paid TV channels and exclusive user generated content&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Its parent company, Google, is best at the advertising game among all players&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Peacock&lt;/strong&gt; is an interesting player because it has 3 very popular assets: NBC sports, NBC news and Bravo - all essential to a typical household&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;However their business model is poor because it is under-priced&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MN: In this industry, I can’t blame Peacock because Paramount did it. If you look at the original, the Disney Plus launch way back in 2019, that was exceptionally cheap. They all failed to raise prices during the pandemic the way Netflix did because it was an essential good, it was like selling a mask. You’re stuck at home, you have to watch something, we’re going to raise prices. If they’re too slow to raise prices, therefore they create deflation within the entertainment channel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Netflix&lt;/strong&gt; has the best leverage in terms of content spending&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Having the largest subscribe base gives them the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/stratechery-netflix-earnings-q4-24/&#34;&gt;best buying and pricing power&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sports events are indeed driving new subscriber signups even if they denied so, because they are buying more sports events:&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;They buy sports events when there is value but they don&amp;rsquo;t depend on those to survive, unlike their competitors&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;don’t judge them by what they say, judge them by what they do.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tech industry spends like media companies in the streaming wars&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;around 2015 tech companies are bullish because the shift to digital advertising just started&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;since ChatGPT launched, companies have enormous capital expenses that do not convert to revenue&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Alphabet CapEx being the most defensible because their cloud business is limited by capacity&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;CapEx spent a few years ago start slowly showing up as depreciation&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Meta and Alphabet as investment options&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Meta was great when it got sold because of CapEx&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;now its CapEx would start showing up, plus its year of efficiency benefit comes to an end&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Search is a declining business but not dead yet - quite the opposite, it&amp;rsquo;s growing in double digits (~13% for at least the past 3 quarters)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The market has not priced in the search growth because it is focused on the narrative around AI eating search market share&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;both companies have a tangible business use case for generative AI: digital ad&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;macro conditions are going to perhaps affect the cyclicality of these businesses&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are more discussions about topics like being an analysts in the AI era, future of the sports media, etc that are not covered here.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Practical Guide to Managing iPhone Photos/Videos</title>
      <link>https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/a-practical-guide-to-managing-iphone-photos-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 20:45:58 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/a-practical-guide-to-managing-iphone-photos-videos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Managing family photos can feel like a never-ending battle. If you&amp;rsquo;re anything like me, your iPhone is bursting with thousands of pictures and videos — vacations, birthdays, random shots of the pet or the kid doing something vaguely interesting. But when it comes to storing them, the default option, iCloud, isn&amp;rsquo;t always the best fit. Maybe you&amp;rsquo;re wary of subscription fees, or you just don&amp;rsquo;t trust your memories to live entirely in the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This post walks through all the photo storage options I explored and why I ultimately decided on syncing my iPhone photos to a local drive. If you&amp;rsquo;re okay with a bit of manual work and want a solution that’s cost-effective and reliable, this might be the right choice for you too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;option-1-cloud-storage-services&#34;&gt;Option 1: Cloud Storage Services&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cloud services like iCloud, Google Photos, and Amazon Photos are the most obvious and maybe most convenient options: automatic uploads, easy sharing, and access from anywhere. In particular, iCloud has great integrations with iPhones that our family use (so does Google Photos to Android phones).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iCloud&lt;/strong&gt;: Free 5GB, best integration with iPhones and Apple devices&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google Photos&lt;/strong&gt;: Free 15 GB (shared with Gmail/Drive), great AI features, supports Live Photos.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Microsoft OneDrive&lt;/strong&gt;: Free 5 GB; integrates well with Windows and Office apps.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amazon Photos&lt;/strong&gt;: Free unlimited photo storage for Prime members; supports Live Photos.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dropbox&lt;/strong&gt;: Simple but expensive ($9.99/month for 2 TB); splits Live Photos into separate files.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pCloud&lt;/strong&gt;: Lifetime plans available but lacks the seamless integration of others.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-i-passed-on-cloud-services&#34;&gt;Why I Passed on Cloud Services&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This option can be deceptively expensive. Storage need is one of the things that only grows: when&amp;rsquo;s the last time you really organize and even delete photos or videos? Especially for family, even a off-focus photo of the kid is too precious to throw away. Under such context, once a family starts using a storage solution, it is just a destined road towards its most expensive plan.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;option-2-building-my-own-cloud&#34;&gt;Option 2: Building My Own Cloud&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The DIY route sounded tempting at first. With tools like Nextcloud or Immich, I could create a private cloud server hosted on my own hardware. This would give me full control over my data while mimicking the convenience of commercial cloud services.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-i-passed-on-diy-cloud&#34;&gt;Why I Passed on DIY Cloud&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As much as I liked the idea of owning my own cloud, the setup process was daunting. Between configuring hardware (like a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network-attached_storage&#34;&gt;network attached storage&lt;/a&gt;) and maintaining software updates, it felt like trading one headache for another. Plus, while these solutions can preserve Live Photos (the iPhone feature that combines still images with short videos), getting it right requires technical know-how.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;option-3-semi-manual-transfer-to-local-storage&#34;&gt;Option 3: Semi-Manual Transfer to Local Storage&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is where things started to click for me: transferring photos from my iPhone to a local drive or computer manually. It’s not as flashy as cloud sync or as technical as building your own solution, but it gets the job done without recurring costs or privacy concerns. Modern iPhones (i.e. ones with USB-C ports) even supports to transfer to External USB drives directly!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here are the two main approaches:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;direct-transfer-to-external-usb-drives&#34;&gt;Direct Transfer to External USB Drives&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Plug in an external drive.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Open the Photos app and select &amp;ldquo;Export Unmodified Originals&amp;rdquo; to preserve Live Photos.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Save directly to the drive using the Files app.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;transfer-via-computer&#34;&gt;Transfer via Computer&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Connect your iPhone to your computer (macOS Finder or Windows File Explorer works fine).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Use tools like CopyTrans Photo (Windows) or Finder (macOS) to drag-and-drop photos onto an external hard drive.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;For better organization and metadata preservation (including Live Photos), apps like PhotoSync or Simple Transfer streamline the process.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Of course there are many 3rd-party sync software (e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.photosync-app.com/home&#34;&gt;PhotoSync&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://rambax.com/simpletransfer&#34;&gt;Simple Transfer&lt;/a&gt;) that offers more feature like automatically sync or sync to a network attached storage, but I find direct wired transfer - no pun intended - is still the best balancing of speed, privacy and effort.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-local-sync-works-for-me&#34;&gt;Why Local Sync Works for Me&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After trying multiple solutions, syncing photos and videos manually to a local drive struck the perfect balance between effort and control. Here’s why:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost&lt;/strong&gt;: No subscriptions or recurring fees—just a one-time purchase of an external hard drive.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Privacy&lt;/strong&gt;: My photos stay offline unless I choose otherwise.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simplicity&lt;/strong&gt;: The process is straightforward enough that even non-tech-savvy family members can follow it.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Live Photo Preservation&lt;/strong&gt;: By using “Export Unmodified Originals,” both the still image and video components of Live Photos remain intact.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-thoughts&#34;&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In an era where everything is moving to the cloud, it feels oddly satisfying to keep something tangible—like an external hard drive full of family memories. Sure, transferring photos manually takes a little effort now and then, but there’s something reassuring about knowing exactly where my data lives.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you’re okay with rolling up your sleeves occasionally and want a solution that’s affordable and private, syncing photos locally might be your best bet too. It’s not glamorous, but sometimes simple just works.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reading &#34;an Interview With Benedict Evans About Ai Unknowns&#34;</title>
      <link>https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/reading-stratechery-an-interview-with-benedict-evans-about-ai-unknowns/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 20:31:42 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/reading-stratechery-an-interview-with-benedict-evans-about-ai-unknowns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://stratechery.com/2025/an-interview-with-benedict-evans-about-ai-unknowns/&#34;&gt;Stratechery&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;BE: This is a much bigger deal if you’re in the accounting industry than if you’re in the cement industry.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s a great thing if you’re in the cement industry, data centers need foundations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;BE: Well, if you’re in the cement industry, this probably means you’re using new software.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yep.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;BE: If you’re in the accounting industry, this changes the whole nature of your industry, so that’s one observation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Evans (i.e. BE) is talking about the impact of AI softwares over different industries - huge for accounting industry but little for the cement industry.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The conversation is pertinent to me, as someone works in the tech industry, where AI impact is probably among the most - just look at numerous stories of people using AI coding agents to build working softwares without the help of developers at all. How to survive the wave of AI?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The answer seem to be starting a side business in an industry or sector that are intrinsically resilient towards AI. Now it is probably not feasible for me to get into cement industry, but generally businesses that built around physical goods/locations or people could be promising: physical shop owner, fitness trainer, landlord, blue collar jobs etc. AI is not likely able to replace any of them in the near future. On the contrary, it is possible to even leverage AI to improve the business.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investment Update - January 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/investment-update-01-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 14:57:58 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/investment-update-01-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is our monthly update on the family fund’s investment performance for January 2025. It highlights this month’s changes, with a full month-over-month trend analysis coming soon as a separate page.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This first update is longer than usual, as it explains the &amp;ldquo;why&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;how&amp;rdquo; behind it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-writing-this-update&#34;&gt;Why writing this update&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For years, we’ve casually traded stocks with our family fund, like typical retail traders. Honestly, we’re not great at it—our results just follow the market, and we’ve only tracked them through tax returns. Still, managing our money well matters to us.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We think regular updates will:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Show how our money’s doing (it’s not a lot, but it matters to us)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sharpen our trading skills by reviewing changes and trades&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Keep us focused on this as a family priority&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;May spark helpful online feedback&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-does-the-update-include&#34;&gt;What does the update include&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our fund mixes 401(k) contributions—a U.S. employer-sponsored retirement plan with pre-tax, tax-deferred growth—and after-tax money once the 401(k) is maxed out. Our 401(k) is mostly in retirement fund and US market index fund. With after-tax funds, we trade individual stocks, index funds, crypto, and also use robo-investing for a part of it (automated, low-fee portfolio management). We’re curious to compare robo-investing’s results to our manual investment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We report normalized values, with the starting point of total value being 100 (as of 01/01/2025), not actual dollars, for privacy reasons.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We’re shifting from heavy individual stock holdings to mostly U.S. index funds for long-term growth and low fees. We’ll keep some stocks for long-term gains and a small chunk for short-term trading. The updates won&amp;rsquo;t detail these breakdowns until they stabilize—numbers jump too much otherwise, making updates meaningless.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this first update, we report the value change and growth of the total asset and some high level breakdowns. We will add more in the future update.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;january-update&#34;&gt;January update&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Overall, January is a good month. The total value grows to 104.85 by the end of the month. After tax portion grows slightly higher than 401(k), largely because the stock market outperforms in January. Below is the detailed growth rate:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;table&gt;&#xA;  &lt;thead&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;          &lt;th&gt;Growth rate (%)&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/thead&gt;&#xA;  &lt;tbody&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Total asset&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;3.02&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;After tax&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;3.07&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;401(k)&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;2.89&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/tbody&gt;&#xA;&lt;/table&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reading Stratechery analysis on Netflix Earnings Q4 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/stratechery-netflix-earnings-q4-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 21:28:37 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/stratechery-netflix-earnings-q4-24/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://stratechery.com/2025/encryption-and-the-uneasy-compromise-netflix-earnings-the-aggregators-compounding-advantage/&#34;&gt;Stratechery&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While I don’t think Netflix planned it this way, it is quite the flex to report record subscriber ads in the last quarter where they will report that number as a matter of course. I thought the reporting change was reasonable, but I also thought that part of the reason for the reporting change was because the password-sharing crackdown represented the last big growth surge. I guess not!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Netflix executives on the earnings call strongly disagreed with an analyst who assumed that the Mike Tyson-Jake Paul boxing event and Christmas Day NFL games were the primary drivers of that subscriber growth, crediting them with only “a small minority of our total member acquisition in the quarter”; that said, executives also spoke very positively about the events and that they would do more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Neither password crackdown nor live stream events are the main driver of the subscriber growth, the growth is organic then?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This makes total sense, and is a worthy extension of Aggregation Theory. Specifically, while more subscribers means that Netflix can spend more on content, thus attracting more subscribers, more content also means that Netflix can drive more engagement on a per-customer basis — there’s just more to watch! This, in Netflix’s case, provides “permission” to raise prices&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The benefit of being an aggregator, for Netflix, is having both pricing power and buying power.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;pricing power:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;having the largest subscriber base means it needs less revenue per subscriber to achieve the same revenue&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Netflix is indeed getting less revenue per subscriber compared with other streaming competitors&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;as a result, Netflix has more room to increase its subscription fee&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;buying power:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;having the largest subscriber base means it can spread the content cost to more subscribers&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Netflix is indeed having the lowest content spend per subscriber compared with other streaming competitors&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;as a result, Netflix can afford to spend more on content&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These two form a virtuous cycle.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adding an RSS Feed to My Site</title>
      <link>https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/add-rss-to-my-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2025 20:37:30 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/add-rss-to-my-site/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently decided to add an RSS feed to my Hugo website. While it seemed straightforward at first, I ran into several gotchas that taught me more about Hugo&amp;rsquo;s RSS system than I expected to learn.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-simple-solution-that-wasnt-quite-right&#34;&gt;The simple solution that wasn&amp;rsquo;t quite right&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My Hugo theme, Paper, advertises built-in RSS support. I initially tried their &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nanxiaobei/hugo-paper?tab=readme-ov-file#options&#34;&gt;default RSS configuration&lt;/a&gt;, but it had two problems:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The feed only included snippets of each post instead of the full content. This meant subscribers had to click through to my site to read complete articles.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The feed included everything from my website, including non-article pages like my About page. I wanted the feed to focus only on my blog posts.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I could have lived with these limitations, but I prefer to give my readers the best possible experience. For me, that means allowing them to read full articles directly in their RSS reader.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;creating-a-custom-rss-template&#34;&gt;Creating a custom RSS template&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To fix these issues, I needed to create my own RSS template. Hugo&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/templates/rss/&#34;&gt;RSS documentation&lt;/a&gt; pointed me to their &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gohugoio/hugo/blob/master/tpl/tplimpl/embedded/templates/_default/rss.xml&#34;&gt;default RSS template&lt;/a&gt;, which I could use as a starting point.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s where I learned something interesting about Hugo: it has two different types of RSS feeds. There&amp;rsquo;s a &amp;ldquo;home&amp;rdquo; feed that includes all content and a &amp;ldquo;section&amp;rdquo; feed that only includes content from a specific section of your site.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since I wanted my feed to include only blog posts, I created a template called &lt;code&gt;section.rss.xml&lt;/code&gt; rather than &lt;code&gt;home.rss.xml&lt;/code&gt;. This tells Hugo to generate the feed only for my &amp;ldquo;posts&amp;rdquo; section.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The modification to include full content instead of snippets was surprisingly simple. I just had to change one line in the template:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-xml&#34; data-lang=&#34;xml&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;description&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;{% raw %}{{ .Content | transform.XMLEscape | safeHTML }}{% endraw %}&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;/description&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The key change was replacing &lt;code&gt;.Summary&lt;/code&gt; with &lt;code&gt;.Content&lt;/code&gt;. This tells Hugo to include the complete article text in the feed instead of just a preview.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-unexpected-build-failure&#34;&gt;An unexpected build failure&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Just when I thought I was done, Cloudflare Pages refused to build my site. The error message was cryptic:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Error: can&amp;#39;t evaluate field XMLEscape in type interface {}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;After some digging, I discovered that the &lt;code&gt;XMLEscape&lt;/code&gt; function I was using wasn&amp;rsquo;t available in the version of Hugo (v0.118.2) that Cloudflare Pages was using. The function was only added in Hugo v0.121.0.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, Cloudflare Pages lets you &lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.cloudflare.com/pages/framework-guides/deploy-a-hugo-site/#use-a-specific-or-newer-hugo-version&#34;&gt;specify which Hugo version to use&lt;/a&gt;. I added this to my build configuration &lt;code&gt;HUGO_VERSION = &amp;quot;v0.144.2&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;one-last-tweak-fixing-the-rss-icon&#34;&gt;One last tweak: fixing the RSS icon&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With the build working, I noticed one final issue: the RSS icon in my site&amp;rsquo;s header still pointed to the home feed (&lt;code&gt;/index.xml&lt;/code&gt;) instead of my new section feed (&lt;code&gt;/posts/index.xml&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To fix this, I needed to override the theme&amp;rsquo;s header template. I copied the theme&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;layouts/partials/header.html&lt;/code&gt; to my site and modified the RSS link from &lt;code&gt;index.xml&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;posts/index.xml&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;href=&amp;#34;{{ if eq . `rss` }}&#xA;        {{ `posts/index.xml` | absURL }} &amp;lt;--- change this line&#xA;      {{ else if eq . `mastodon` }}&#xA;        {{ index site.Params . }}&#xA;      {{ else }}&#xA;        {{ if eq . `threads` }}&#xA;          https://threads.net/&#xA;        {{ else if eq . `bluesky` }}&#xA;          https://bsky.app/profile/&#xA;          {{ else }}&#xA;            https://{{ . }}.com/&#xA;          {{ if eq . `linkedin` }}&#xA;            in/&#xA;          {{ end }}&#xA;        {{ end }}&#xA;        {{ index site.Params . }}&#xA;      {{ end }}&amp;#34;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;This way, it generates the URL to be &lt;code&gt;{my-website-url}/posts/index.xml&lt;/code&gt;, instead of &lt;code&gt;{my-website-url}/index.xml&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-end-result&#34;&gt;The end result&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After these changes, my site now has exactly the RSS feed I wanted:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Full article content in the feed&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Only blog posts (no auxiliary pages)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Proper RSS icon linking to the correct feed URL&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While this took more work than I expected, I&amp;rsquo;m happy with the result. My readers can now enjoy my full articles directly in their RSS readers, which is exactly what I wanted.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The whole process taught me quite a bit about Hugo&amp;rsquo;s RSS system and reminded me that even seemingly simple features can require diving deeper into a framework&amp;rsquo;s internals than you might expect.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let me know in the comments if you&amp;rsquo;ve had similar experiences setting up RSS feeds, or if you have any questions about the process!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I add tags to the posts</title>
      <link>https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/add-tags/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 11:03:03 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/add-tags/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I added tags to my posts so that each post has its own set of tags to give you an idea what the content is about. It looks like this at the bottom of the post:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/tags_screenshot.png&#34; alt=&#34;Tags in a post&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In fact, Hugo has tags support by default. The system is called &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/content-management/taxonomies/&#34;&gt;Taxonomies&lt;/a&gt;. It allows users to freely define categorizations that can be used to classify the content. For example, if my blog is movie reviews, then I can create a Taxonomy called genre, and label each post based on the type of the movie it reviews. The good news is Hugo creates a Taxonomy called &lt;code&gt;tags&lt;/code&gt; already for users (as well as &lt;code&gt;categorization&lt;/code&gt;). To add tags to a post, I just need to put them in the front matter of the post. The code below shows the front matter of this post with tags added:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;+++&#xA;date = &amp;#39;2025-02-16T20:00:01-08:00&amp;#39;&#xA;draft = true&#xA;title = &amp;#39;I add tags to the posts&amp;#39;&#xA;tags = [&amp;#39;howto&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;blog-setup&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;tags&amp;#39;]&#xA;+++&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;With tags on each post, there are 2 more features I can add. The first one is to list all tags used in my blog, and it looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/taxonomy_list_screenshot.png&#34; alt=&#34;A page showing all tags created&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To enable this, I simply add &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/templates/taxonomy/&#34;&gt;this template&lt;/a&gt; provided by Hugo to my site at &lt;code&gt;my-hugo-site/layouts/_default/taxonomy.html&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Another one is to show all the posts that use a particular tag when someone clicks a tag in the post, and it looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/term_page_screenshot.png&#34; alt=&#34;A page showing all posts use this tag&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To enable this, I add &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/templates/term/&#34;&gt;another Hugo template&lt;/a&gt; to my site as a file at &lt;code&gt;my-hugo-site/layouts/_default/term.html&lt;/code&gt;. A &lt;code&gt;term&lt;/code&gt; means a key or an item of a certain taxonomy - in the &lt;code&gt;tags&lt;/code&gt; taxonomy, it means a tag.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One issue I notice after setting everything up is the link of each tag in a post is wrong. It should look like &lt;code&gt;{my-website-url}/tags/{the-tag-name}&lt;/code&gt;, so that when someone clicks it it takes them to the &lt;code&gt;term&lt;/code&gt; page I add above. Instead, it looks like &lt;code&gt;{my-website-url}posts/{this-post}/tags/{the-tag-name}&lt;/code&gt;, resulting a &lt;code&gt;page not found (404)&lt;/code&gt; error if I click it. The root cause is in the Hugo theme I use. In its post template, it uses &lt;code&gt;tags/{the-tag-name}&lt;/code&gt; as the hyperlink instead of &lt;code&gt;/tags/{the-tag-name}&lt;/code&gt;: the former is always treated as the postfix to be appended to the &lt;strong&gt;current URL&lt;/strong&gt; (the post link), while the latter to the root URL (my website url). Adding the forward slash fixes the issue.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although to fix the issue, I have to copy and paste the template in question (&lt;code&gt;my-hugo-site/themes/paper/layouts/_default/single.html&lt;/code&gt;) to my template folder (&lt;code&gt;my-hugo-site/layouts/_default/single.html&lt;/code&gt;) to modifty it so that the latter overrides the former when Hugo generates the website.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I give my website a name</title>
      <link>https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/add-a-custom-domain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 09:56:04 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/add-a-custom-domain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My website has a name and a domain now, and looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/blog_screenshot_with_name.png&#34; alt=&#34;My website has a name now&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article talks about how I come up with the name and set up the website under the new domain.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this site is so I can write. The reason I am writing is two: 1. remember stuff for me; 2. sharing stuff I did. It is basically a journal. The consistency of journaling and writing in general is chanllenging, so I want to keep my hopes low. All in all, &amp;ldquo;Mildly Journaling&amp;rdquo; sounds like what this site intends to be.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;More importantly, the domain &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mildlyjournaling.com&#34;&gt;www.mildlyjournaling.com&lt;/a&gt; is available for cheap price ($10 a year). I bought the domain and followed &lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.cloudflare.com/pages/configuration/custom-domains/&#34;&gt;this instruction&lt;/a&gt; to map the domain to my website hosted on Cloudflare Pages.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To change the name of the website so the content there actually says this name, I just modify the &lt;code&gt;hugo.toml&lt;/code&gt; file in the root directory of the website files locally. Now the file looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;languageCode = &amp;#39;en-us&amp;#39;&#xA;title = &amp;#39;Mildly Journaling&amp;#39;&#xA;theme = &amp;#39;paper&amp;#39;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I set up my blog</title>
      <link>https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 20:04:32 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I created yet another blog to write stuff. Here is what it looks like:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/blog_screenshot.png&#34; alt=&#34;What does my blog look like&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This blog talks about what did I do to set it up. It is created using Hugo, and hosted on Cloudflare Pages via Github. All free.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hugo is a free tool that takes simple text I write and turns it into a blog website. Cloudflare Pages is a platform to host the actual website I create on the Internet. Github is a platform to store code (or really anything digitally), track changes and open to others for e.g. sharing and collaboration. Some basic knowledge of the three tools would make reading the following a bit easier, but not required.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The rest of blog walks through the how-to step by step:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Use Hugo locally to create the blog&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Setup Github to host and track the Hugo files&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Deploy the blog to Cloudflare Pages&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;use-hugo-to-create-the-blog&#34;&gt;Use Hugo to create the blog&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First of all I setup Hugo locally to create the blog. Practically speaking, it means I need to use tools Hugo provides to generate a bunch of files that are used to configure how does my site look and feel, and then another bunch of files generated based the first bunch that actually represent my website (like a HTML file of the home page). My laptop is a Macbook so I follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/installation/macos/#homebrew&#34;&gt;this instruction&lt;/a&gt; to install Hugo. I then follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/getting-started/quick-start/&#34;&gt;this Hugo documentation page&lt;/a&gt; to create a new site, select a theme for the site, and create a new blog to the site, all in one folder. The folder looks roughly like below. Each subfolder &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/getting-started/directory-structure/#site-skeleton&#34;&gt;serves its own usage&lt;/a&gt;, but for now only a few are relevant as pointed out below.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;my-hugo-site/&#xA;├── archetypes/&#xA;├── assets/&#xA;├── content/         &amp;lt;-- the actual blog content is here&#xA;│   └── posts/       &amp;lt;-- blog posts&#xA;├── data/&#xA;├── i18n/&#xA;├── layouts/&#xA;├── public/&#xA;├── static/&#xA;├── themes/          &#xA;│   └── paper/       &amp;lt;-- the theme you selected&#xA;└── hugo.toml        &amp;lt;-- the site configuration&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Besides deploying to Cloudflare Pages, it is also possible to run the blog locally on my laptop by issuing this command under the site root folder &lt;code&gt;my-hugo-site&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo server -D&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;The flag &lt;code&gt;-D&lt;/code&gt; is to tell Hugo to include draft posts in the blog as well. When I create a post, by default Hugo marks it as a draft by adding the line &lt;code&gt;draft = true&lt;/code&gt; in the post. Without the flag, draft posts won&amp;rsquo;t show up as blogs in the website. Alternatively, removing that line from the post &amp;ldquo;publishes&amp;rdquo; the post and Hugo would include it automatically.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;setup-github-to-host-and-track-the-blog&#34;&gt;Setup Github to host and track the blog&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Practically speaking, this step puts the files of my blog somewhere on the Internet to be discoverable and readable. It also enables easy integrations with other servides such as Cloudflare Pages. It is necessary to automate the deployment to Cloudflare Pages.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is a plenty of tutorials on how to create a new repository in Github and push the local files to the repository. I won&amp;rsquo;t cover it as I didn&amp;rsquo;t do anything extra or special here. The only thing to mention is that to push to the repository hosted online at Github, I need to authenticate myself with my Github credentials. Unfortunately, Github has disabled using password as part of the credentials there - one has to use either &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.github.com/en/authentication/keeping-your-account-and-data-secure/managing-your-personal-access-tokens&#34;&gt;an access token&lt;/a&gt; or rely on special tools like Github command line tool. This is quite complex.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;deploy-the-blog-to-cloudflare-pages&#34;&gt;Deploy the blog to Cloudflare Pages&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One might wonder: didn&amp;rsquo;t we already use Github to host the blog, why do we need this step? Github is more of a file storage, if you will, with other features such as collaboration and version tracking. It requires a computer to process the blog files and render them into a website when visitors come. That is what Cloudflare Pages does.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cloudflare Pages supports integrating with Github such that every time there&amp;rsquo;s a new change in the Github repository (that I push in from my local version), it automatically fetches all the file and deloy them again, ensuring the website it renders always stays at the latest.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I follow the instruction &lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.cloudflare.com/pages/framework-guides/deploy-a-hugo-site/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; provided by Cloudflare. Steps are straightfoward except one thing: remember to remove the line &lt;code&gt;baseurl = &amp;quot;https://example.com&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; from the &lt;code&gt;hugo.toml&lt;/code&gt; configuration file. This line is automatically generated when I generate the site, but is wrong because it points to a fake website as an example. This is supposed to tell Hugo the full URL of the website for various purpose. Removing it does not hurt the basic functionality, and I can add it back when I do have an actual URL/domain for my blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it! I have a blog again.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Features of this website as of 2/17/2025</title>
      <link>https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/blog-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 16:44:37 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/blog-features/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I want a place to track notable features of this website for reference. This post will be a bit different from others, as it will get periodically updated as this website gets more features.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; 2/17/2025 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/add-tags&#34;&gt;tags per post, tag page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; 2/16/2025 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mildlyjournaling.com/posts/add-a-custom-domain&#34;&gt;custom domain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>