<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>posts on Mildly Journaling</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in posts on Mildly Journaling</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 06:37:30 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Add RSS to My Site</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/add-rss-to-my-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 06:37:30 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/add-rss-to-my-site/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;theme has a way to enable RSS, but that feed has only description, not full text, and it includes pages like About&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;change it from &lt;code&gt;.Summary&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;.Content&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;item&amp;gt;&#xA;  &amp;lt;title&amp;gt;{{ .Title }}&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;&#xA;  &amp;lt;link&amp;gt;{{ .Permalink }}&amp;lt;/link&amp;gt;&#xA;  &amp;lt;pubDate&amp;gt;{{ .PublishDate.Format &amp;#34;Mon, 02 Jan 2006 15:04:05 -0700&amp;#34; | safeHTML }}&amp;lt;/pubDate&amp;gt;&#xA;  {{- with $authorEmail }}&amp;lt;author&amp;gt;{{ . }}{{ with $authorName }} ({{ . }}){{ end }}&amp;lt;/author&amp;gt;{{ end }}&#xA;  &amp;lt;guid&amp;gt;{{ .Permalink }}&amp;lt;/guid&amp;gt;&#xA;  &amp;lt;description&amp;gt;{{ .Content | transform.XMLEscape | safeHTML }}&amp;lt;/description&amp;gt;&#xA;&amp;lt;/item&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I add tags to the posts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/add-tags/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 11:03:03 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/add-tags/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I added tags to my posts so that each post has its own set of tags to give you an idea what the content is about. It looks like this at the bottom of the post:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/tags_screenshot.png&#34; alt=&#34;Tags in a post&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In fact, Hugo has tags support by default. The system is called &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/content-management/taxonomies/&#34;&gt;Taxonomies&lt;/a&gt;. It allows users to freely define categorizations that can be used to classify the content. For example, if my blog is movie reviews, then I can create a Taxonomy called genre, and label each post based on the type of the movie it reviews. The good news is Hugo creates a Taxonomy called &lt;code&gt;tags&lt;/code&gt; already for users (as well as &lt;code&gt;categorization&lt;/code&gt;). To add tags to a post, I just need to put them in the front matter of the post. The code below shows the front matter of this post with tags added:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;+++&#xA;date = &amp;#39;2025-02-16T20:00:01-08:00&amp;#39;&#xA;draft = true&#xA;title = &amp;#39;I add tags to the posts&amp;#39;&#xA;tags = [&amp;#39;howto&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;blog-setup&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;tags&amp;#39;]&#xA;+++&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;With tags on each post, there are 2 more features I can add. The first one is to list all tags used in my blog, and it looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/taxonomy_list_screenshot.png&#34; alt=&#34;A page showing all tags created&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To enable this, I simply add &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/templates/taxonomy/&#34;&gt;this template&lt;/a&gt; provided by Hugo to my site at &lt;code&gt;my-hugo-site/layouts/_default/taxonomy.html&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Another one is to show all the posts that use a particular tag when someone clicks a tag in the post, and it looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/term_page_screenshot.png&#34; alt=&#34;A page showing all posts use this tag&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To enable this, I add &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/templates/term/&#34;&gt;another Hugo template&lt;/a&gt; to my site as a file at &lt;code&gt;my-hugo-site/layouts/_default/term.html&lt;/code&gt;. A &lt;code&gt;term&lt;/code&gt; means a key or an item of a certain taxonomy - in the &lt;code&gt;tags&lt;/code&gt; taxonomy, it means a tag.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One issue I notice after setting everything up is the link of each tag in a post is wrong. It should look like &lt;code&gt;{my-website-url}/tags/{the-tag-name}&lt;/code&gt;, so that when someone clicks it it takes them to the &lt;code&gt;term&lt;/code&gt; page I add above. Instead, it looks like &lt;code&gt;{my-website-url}posts/{this-post}/tags/{the-tag-name}&lt;/code&gt;, resulting a &lt;code&gt;page not found (404)&lt;/code&gt; error if I click it. The root cause is in the Hugo theme I use. In its post template, it uses &lt;code&gt;tags/{the-tag-name}&lt;/code&gt; as the hyperlink instead of &lt;code&gt;/tags/{the-tag-name}&lt;/code&gt;: the former is always treated as the postfix to be appended to the &lt;strong&gt;current URL&lt;/strong&gt; (the post link), while the latter to the root URL (my website url). Adding the forward slash fixes the issue.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although to fix the issue, I have to copy and paste the template in question (&lt;code&gt;my-hugo-site/themes/paper/layouts/_default/single.html&lt;/code&gt;) to my template folder (&lt;code&gt;my-hugo-site/layouts/_default/single.html&lt;/code&gt;) to modifty it so that the latter overrides the former when Hugo generates the website.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I give my website a name</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/add-a-custom-domain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 09:56:04 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/add-a-custom-domain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My website has a name and a domain now, and looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/blog_screenshot_with_name.png&#34; alt=&#34;My website has a name now&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article talks about how I come up with the name and set up the website under the new domain.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this site is so I can write. The reason I am writing is two: 1. remember stuff for me; 2. sharing stuff I did. It is basically a journal. The consistency of journaling and writing in general is chanllenging, so I want to keep my hopes low. All in all, &amp;ldquo;Mildly Journaling&amp;rdquo; sounds like what this site intends to be.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;More importantly, the domain &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mildlyjournaling.com&#34;&gt;www.mildlyjournaling.com&lt;/a&gt; is available for cheap price ($10 a year). I bought the domain and followed &lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.cloudflare.com/pages/configuration/custom-domains/&#34;&gt;this instruction&lt;/a&gt; to map the domain to my website hosted on Cloudflare Pages.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To change the name of the website so the content there actually says this name, I just modify the &lt;code&gt;hugo.toml&lt;/code&gt; file in the root directory of the website files locally. Now the file looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;languageCode = &amp;#39;en-us&amp;#39;&#xA;title = &amp;#39;Mildly Journaling&amp;#39;&#xA;theme = &amp;#39;paper&amp;#39;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I set up my blog</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 20:04:32 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I created yet another blog to write stuff. Here is what it looks like:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/blog_screenshot.png&#34; alt=&#34;What does my blog look like&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This blog talks about what did I do to set it up. It is created using Hugo, and hosted on Cloudflare Pages via Github. All free.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hugo is a free tool that takes simple text I write and turns it into a blog website. Cloudflare Pages is a platform to host the actual website I create on the Internet. Github is a platform to store code (or really anything digitally), track changes and open to others for e.g. sharing and collaboration. Some basic knowledge of the three tools would make reading the following a bit easier, but not required.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The rest of blog walks through the how-to step by step:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Use Hugo locally to create the blog&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Setup Github to host and track the Hugo files&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Deploy the blog to Cloudflare Pages&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;use-hugo-to-create-the-blog&#34;&gt;Use Hugo to create the blog&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First of all I setup Hugo locally to create the blog. Practically speaking, it means I need to use tools Hugo provides to generate a bunch of files that are used to configure how does my site look and feel, and then another bunch of files generated based the first bunch that actually represent my website (like a HTML file of the home page). My laptop is a Macbook so I follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/installation/macos/#homebrew&#34;&gt;this instruction&lt;/a&gt; to install Hugo. I then follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/getting-started/quick-start/&#34;&gt;this Hugo documentation page&lt;/a&gt; to create a new site, select a theme for the site, and create a new blog to the site, all in one folder. The folder looks roughly like below. Each subfolder &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/getting-started/directory-structure/#site-skeleton&#34;&gt;serves its own usage&lt;/a&gt;, but for now only a few are relevant as pointed out below.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;my-hugo-site/&#xA;├── archetypes/&#xA;├── assets/&#xA;├── content/         &amp;lt;-- the actual blog content is here&#xA;│   └── posts/       &amp;lt;-- blog posts&#xA;├── data/&#xA;├── i18n/&#xA;├── layouts/&#xA;├── public/&#xA;├── static/&#xA;├── themes/          &#xA;│   └── paper/       &amp;lt;-- the theme you selected&#xA;└── hugo.toml        &amp;lt;-- the site configuration&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Besides deploying to Cloudflare Pages, it is also possible to run the blog locally on my laptop by issuing this command under the site root folder &lt;code&gt;my-hugo-site&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo server -D&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;The flag &lt;code&gt;-D&lt;/code&gt; is to tell Hugo to include draft posts in the blog as well. When I create a post, by default Hugo marks it as a draft by adding the line &lt;code&gt;draft = true&lt;/code&gt; in the post. Without the flag, draft posts won&amp;rsquo;t show up as blogs in the website. Alternatively, removing that line from the post &amp;ldquo;publishes&amp;rdquo; the post and Hugo would include it automatically.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;setup-github-to-host-and-track-the-blog&#34;&gt;Setup Github to host and track the blog&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Practically speaking, this step puts the files of my blog somewhere on the Internet to be discoverable and readable. It also enables easy integrations with other servides such as Cloudflare Pages. It is necessary to automate the deployment to Cloudflare Pages.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is a plenty of tutorials on how to create a new repository in Github and push the local files to the repository. I won&amp;rsquo;t cover it as I didn&amp;rsquo;t do anything extra or special here. The only thing to mention is that to push to the repository hosted online at Github, I need to authenticate myself with my Github credentials. Unfortunately, Github has disabled using password as part of the credentials there - one has to use either &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.github.com/en/authentication/keeping-your-account-and-data-secure/managing-your-personal-access-tokens&#34;&gt;an access token&lt;/a&gt; or rely on special tools like Github command line tool. This is quite complex.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;deploy-the-blog-to-cloudflare-pages&#34;&gt;Deploy the blog to Cloudflare Pages&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One might wonder: didn&amp;rsquo;t we already use Github to host the blog, why do we need this step? Github is more of a file storage, if you will, with other features such as collaboration and version tracking. It requires a computer to process the blog files and render them into a website when visitors come. That is what Cloudflare Pages does.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cloudflare Pages supports integrating with Github such that every time there&amp;rsquo;s a new change in the Github repository (that I push in from my local version), it automatically fetches all the file and deloy them again, ensuring the website it renders always stays at the latest.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I follow the instruction &lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.cloudflare.com/pages/framework-guides/deploy-a-hugo-site/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; provided by Cloudflare. Steps are straightfoward except one thing: remember to remove the line &lt;code&gt;baseurl = &amp;quot;https://example.com&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; from the &lt;code&gt;hugo.toml&lt;/code&gt; configuration file. This line is automatically generated when I generate the site, but is wrong because it points to a fake website as an example. This is supposed to tell Hugo the full URL of the website for various purpose. Removing it does not hurt the basic functionality, and I can add it back when I do have an actual URL/domain for my blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it! I have a blog again.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Features of this website as of 2/17/2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/blog-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 16:44:37 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/blog-features/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I want a place to track notable features of this website for reference. This post will be a bit different from others, as it will get periodically updated as this website gets more features.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; 2/17/2025 &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/add-tags&#34;&gt;tags per post, tag page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; 2/16/2025 &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/add-a-custom-domain&#34;&gt;custom domain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>