<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mildly Journaling</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mildly Journaling</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 15:51:28 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 15:51:28 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Journaling down stuff here one piece at a time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I add tags to the posts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/add-tags/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 11:03:03 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/add-tags/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I added tags to my posts so that each post has its own set of tags to give you an idea what the content is about. It looks like this at the bottom of the post:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/tags_screenshot.png&#34; alt=&#34;Tags in a post&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In fact, Hugo has tags support by default. The system is called &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/content-management/taxonomies/&#34;&gt;Taxonomies&lt;/a&gt;. It allows users to freely define categorizations that can be used to classify the content. For example, if my blog is movie reviews, then I can create a Taxonomy called genre, and label each post based on the type of the movie it reviews. The good news is Hugo creates a Taxonomy called &lt;code&gt;tags&lt;/code&gt; already for users (as well as &lt;code&gt;categorization&lt;/code&gt;). To add tags to a post, I just need to put them in the front matter of the post. The code below shows the front matter of this post with tags added:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I give my website a name</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/add-a-custom-domain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 09:56:04 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/add-a-custom-domain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My website has a name and a domain now, and looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/blog_screenshot_with_name.png&#34; alt=&#34;My website has a name now&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article talks about how I come up with the name and set up the website under the new domain.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this site is so I can write. The reason I am writing is two: 1. remember stuff for me; 2. sharing stuff I did. It is basically a journal. The consistency of journaling and writing in general is chanllenging, so I want to keep my hopes low. All in all, &amp;ldquo;Mildly Journaling&amp;rdquo; sounds like what this site intends to be.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I set up my blog</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 20:04:32 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I created yet another blog to write stuff. Here is what it looks like:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/blog_screenshot.png&#34; alt=&#34;What does my blog look like&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This blog talks about what did I do to set it up. It is created using Hugo, and hosted on Cloudflare Pages via Github. All free.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hugo is a free tool that takes simple text I write and turns it into a blog website. Cloudflare Pages is a platform to host the actual website I create on the Internet. Github is a platform to store code (or really anything digitally), track changes and open to others for e.g. sharing and collaboration. Some basic knowledge of the three tools would make reading the following a bit easier, but not required.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
